

# **Adam Fisher**

**6** 07/02/1973

✓ adamm733@gmail.com

**\** 704-806-4961

Profile

Solution Architect and Full-Stack developer with leading experience.

Working in finance for 20 years I have a wealth of experience in Web & Digital Platform Architecture, preparing for cloud migrations, deconstructing monolithic applications, mapping out DevOps workflows, and modernizing the stack to embrace API, containers, micro-services.

In my career I've delivered a multitude of solutions for client experience, sales tools, innovation, and modernization. To the chaos of of multiple languages, frameworks, products, automation technology, and design patterns, I bring a pragmatic focus to solutions.

Work Experience

### Tech Lead 04/2018 – present

Charles Schwab, Charlotte, NC

Working in Schwab's Retirement Technology as a technical lead I am responsible for delivering application architecture guidelines for our third party software solution, aligning SchwabRT to enterprise architecture guidelines, driving new enterprise development patterns.

- Re-architected existing Angular product to utilize Webpack, Module Delineation, AOT, Treeshaking, NGRX State Management resulting in an initial load time from 20 seconds to sub 2 seconds
- Agile development of product features\*
- · Mentoring developers in best practices, training, thought patterns
- Communication of UX Architecture to feature teams
- Code reviews / guidance for feature teams
- Aligning design and development efforts to Schwab enterprise architectural standards
- Design enterprise development patterns using CLI Tooling to allow for horizontal scaling of feature teams

#### **Enterprise projects:**

- 1. Develop unified enterprise wide web UX architecture based on web components to align all front end development platforms (Angular, React, Legacy, ASP, JSP, CMS)
- 2. Integrate 'shared first floor' Core Visual semantic design concept for web and mobile.
- 3. Design channel agnostic business capability interactions to align to shared business services
- 4. Enterprise Developer Alignment define frameworks, abstractions, and tooling

#### **Solutions Architect**

07/2017 - 04/2018

AIG, Charlotte, NC

Working as a Solutions Architect in AIG's Private Client Group I was responsible for delivering architecture guidelines for web and digital deliveries, designing solutions to challenges in our group and provide support and results in following areas:

- AlG.com / My.AlG.com Led a transformation of monolithic stack to an API based stack utilizing Java Spring for Web Services integrating with legacy Java domain services, ReactJS for application framework, and third party digital payment system
- Design & Implement AWS Virtual Private Cloud for Private Client Group, consisting of IAM, Security Groups, IGW, Route Tables, S3, EC2, Autoscale, Apigee, Cloudfront, WAF, Lambda, ELB, Direct Connect, Terraform, and Chef

## Work Experience

 Responsible for delivering architectural guidelines for CMS embedded architecture using Angular 5 and web services provided by Adobe Experience Manager

Tech Lead 12/2016 – 07/2017

AIG, Charlotte, NC

Working as a Tech Lead in AIG's Shared Services Group I was responsible for delivering hybrid native mobile applications for in-house clients using IBM Mobile first platform. Accomplishments:

- Delivered 4 hybrid mobile applications (1 existing, 3 new development)
- Implemented ADM for development team
- Worked with Executive Stakeholders to establish Mobile Center of Excellence based on Forrestor Methodologies (Mobile Moment)
- Created Hybrid Development Patterns to allow for scaling of features by multiple teams
- Led offshore teams in agile development pods

#### **Director, Mobile Development**

01/2016 - 12/2016

Transamerica, Charlotte, NC

As a Director of Mobile Development I was responsible for replacing the existing retirement mobile application, MyTRSRetire, with a hybrid native application, the application was delivered 10/2016.

- Re-designed micro-service architecture from JSP implementation to Java Spring
- Moved source control to enterprise Github
- Architected mobile hybrid platform using Angular 1.x and Apache Cordova
- Integrated IBM Service Access Manager into mobile solution for access control
- Tracked analytics and marketing data using Tealium Audience Stream

#### Director / Senior Dev / Dev

06/2000 - 01/2016

Transamerica, Charlotte, NC

Over a 16 year career at Transamerica I held multiple positions as a developer, senior developer, strategist, and director. Some of my notable accomplishments:

- Personally built in-house green screen recording studio for multimedia projects
- Developed multiple web and mobile applications (financial calcs, augmented reality, event manager)
- Re-engineered current web & mobile offerings customizable for sales
- Created a mobile 'enrollment lab' consisting of tablets for point of contact enrollment in retirement plans
- Designed and developed nationwide kiosk network for major healthcare provider
- Established cloud based tag management system to align marketing automation systems
- Developed interactive retirement forecast modeling engine, winner of Yahoo 100 best sites

Education

#### **Business Administration**

08/1991 - 06/1995

Western Carolina University, Cullowhee, NC

Certifications

#### **AWS Solutions Architect Associate**

11/2017

Amazon

JT0EPP4CCME1QGK8

https://aw.certmetrics.com/amazon/public/verification.aspx

Hobbies











Reading

Travel

Boating

Bulldogs

# Hobbies







DJ

Hiking

Golf